Hi!
In this video clip, I will show you how to check for dangerous parts on toys.
One thing that can make a toy dangerous if it's part come off the toy.
Right here we have a pretend cake.
This candle for instance pops right off so that could cause a choking hazard making it a dangerous toy.
This toy has a cord on it making it a dangerous toy.
The cord can cause the child to strangle them self.
This toy would be okay for the appropriate age.
However, the cord would make it a dangerous toy for younger children.
Another thing to consider is on this toy it needs 3 batteries.
This has a screw making it so that the batteries can't pop out, so this toy would be safe.
However, if it didn't have the screw it would be dangerous for children because the batteries could pop out and they could put them in their mouth.
You also need to make sure that the screw does stay in place and is tightened at all times.
Another thing to consider is checking to make sure there aren't any sharp edges on the toy.
This one has several sharp edges making it a dangerous toy for younger children.
If you used for the appropriate age, it would probably be okay.